

ASHWIN EASO ZACHARIAH

PRODUCT ENGINEER (FULLSTACK & UX)

Email: ashwineaso@gmail.com | Phone: +91 773 678 2213

ABOUT ME

I combine an engineering perspective with a creative problem-solving approach, to create products and experiences that people would love to use. Driven by a passion for design, and the ability to empathize with a user, I pursue challenges that broaden my boundaries.

EXPERIENCE

Sept 2017 - Present

Credy - Product Engineer

Researched, designed and prototyped a consumer-facing web application for analyzing credit reports. Performed user research and A/B testing to achieve a 4% MoM growth in subscription and user retention.

Researched, experimented and designed the loan application flow in both web and android apps, to identify bottlenecks, and reduce dropoff at different stages. Handled full-stack development of the service, assuming the responsibility of Back-end and Front-end development and DevOps management.

Designed and organized a common design system for all internal tools and applications, improving the efficiency of development.

Oct 2015 - Aug 2017

Enguru - Product Engineer

Designed, prototyped and developed the EnguruTalk web application, building an online learning marketplace (engurutalk.com). Discovered and leveraged user insights to quickly pivot product features to suit customer needs.

Wireframed, designed and developed a data analysis and visualization dashboard, for B2B users to track their employee performance while using the enguru application.

Jul 2013 - Sept 2015

Smacon - Software Engineer / UI Designer

Researched, designed and developed modules for a resource management tool for SMEs. Provided onsite training and collected user feedback to improve user experience and features.

EDUCATION

2009 - 2013

Mahatma Gandhi University - Kerala, India

Bachelor Of Technology - Electronics and Communication